<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/remotework/</id>
	<title>remotework on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about remotework</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-02-04T20:29:15Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/remotework/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/remotework/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.54.0">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/04/flow-on-remote-work-and-cafes/</id>
		<title>Flow (on Remote Work and Cafés)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/04/flow-on-remote-work-and-cafes/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-04T20:29:15Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-04T20:29:15Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="flow" label="flow"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="remotework" label="remotework"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="digitalnomad" label="digitalnomad"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I’m a freelancer; I don’t have an office. I can’t work from home; the silence is deafening, I need the background noise, and I need to be among people. The place I work from every day is a café about 25 minutes from my home; it’s called Flow. I am a person of habit: I wake up, I get dressed, I go to Flow and start working.
Flow is one of the many, many specialty cafés in Budapest.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a freelancer; I don&rsquo;t have an office. I can&rsquo;t work from home; the silence is deafening, I need the background noise, and I need to be among people. The place I work from every day is a café about 25 minutes from my home; it&rsquo;s called <a href="https://www.facebook.com/flowcoffeeandbistro/">Flow</a>. I am a person of habit: I wake up, I get dressed, I go to Flow and start working.</p>

<p>Flow is one of the many, many specialty cafés in Budapest. Don&rsquo;t ask me about their coffee: I mostly eschew caffeine — <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/02/re-take-your-pills-my-story-of-adhd/">my ADHD meds</a> mostly replace caffeine — so my regular drink is an iced decaf latte with oat milk. It&rsquo;s one of the most pointless drinks ever, but I like it.</p>

<p>So I don&rsquo;t go to Flow for their coffee, but for everything else. It&rsquo;s big; ceilings about 5 meters high and plenty of space, unlike most cafés. They have fresh pastries delivered every morning; if I get there early enough, I can nab one of my favorite chocolate rolls. And I kinda know some of the people running the place. They used to have great wifi as well, until the people responsible for it installed a network filter on it, blocking random sites and making work impossible. Thank God for unlimited 4G and tethering. They&rsquo;re vegan, and I&rsquo;m a carnivore, but they do have delicious tapioca pudding desserts. That, and plenty of power outlets.</p>

<p>Before Flow, I had another café as my base; before that place, another. I tried coworking spaces, and I was even part of one for about 6 months before the community around it started to dwindle.</p>

<hr />

<p>On weekends or where I&rsquo;m traveling, I go to a Starbucks. They usually have decent wifi, and their decaf is the same everywhere. They&rsquo;re ubiquitous; you can find many of them in most major western cities these days (except for Sweden; there, I&rsquo;ll go to an Espresso House instead).</p>

<hr />

<p>Working from cafés is in many ways is not ideal, but it&rsquo;s the thing that works for me. What <em>would be</em> ideal is a proper office, with coworkers — but I can&rsquo;t give up freelancing for so many reasons. And it&rsquo;s not like I&rsquo;m alone here; I get to hang out with other friends who work remotely.</p>

<p>So cafés it is.</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Flow (on Remote Work and Cafés)”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/04/flow-on-remote-work-and-cafes/">Flow (on Remote Work and Cafés)</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/flow/'>flow</a>, <a href='/tags/remotework/'>remotework</a>, <a href='/tags/digitalnomad/'>digitalnomad</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
