<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writetogether/</id>
	<title>writetogether on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about writetogether</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-02-01T11:46:09Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writetogether/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writetogether/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.53">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/01/converting-my-blog-to-hugo-and-getting-rid-of-my-vps/</id>
		<title>Converting My Blog To Hugo and Getting Rid of My VPS</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/01/converting-my-blog-to-hugo-and-getting-rid-of-my-vps/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-01T11:46:09Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-01T11:46:09Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="meta" label="meta"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="tech" label="tech"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="hugo" label="hugo"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I have a blog (you’re reading it!). It’s got history: I set it up in early 2009, and I have almost 600 posts, mostly in Hungarian. I had one before that, between 2005 and 2008, but it was lost due to a variety of reasons, including my failure to properly back things up. Small bits of it are still up in the Wayback Machine, though. It was all in Wordpress, which does its job, though even in 2019 it can be a pain to update things.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.ktamas.com">I have a blog</a> (you&rsquo;re reading it!). It&rsquo;s got history: I set it up in early 2009, and I have almost 600 posts, mostly in Hungarian. I had one before that, between 2005 and 2008, but it was lost due to a variety of reasons, including my failure to properly back things up. Small bits of it are still <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070208165650/http://blog.ktamas.com/">up in the Wayback Machine</a>, though. It was all in Wordpress, which does its job, though even in 2019 it can be a pain to update things.</p>

<h3 id="from-wordpress-to-jekyll-to-hugo">From Wordpress to Jekyll to Hugo</h3>

<p>About a week ago I decided it was time to migrate it to <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. I was bored, and it gave me a good excuse to play with a static site generator. Plus, doing this kind of conversion became a rite of passage for people working in tech these days.</p>

<p><em>This is not a complete guide; you can find hundreds of them with a <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=convert+wordpress+to+jekyll">quick google</a>. I will, however, provide a general overview of the process with some helpful pointers and links.</em></p>

<p>I started by migrating all the comments to Disqus with their <a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/disqus-comment-system/">official Wordpress plugin</a>. After that, I used a <a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/jekyll-exporter/">Jekyll exporter plugin</a> that converted all my posts into markdown&hellip; except it stripped all the embeds.</p>

<p>I used to blog a lot about music, so I had a lot of embeds, mostly from Youtube. In retrospect, I could have saved myself some time by patching the exporter or finding another one. In the end, however, I ended up fixing every single post by hand. I replaced old, pre-iframe flash embed codes with updated ones and changed the newer, but still http ones to https. In most places, if the video was not necessary or wasn&rsquo;t available anymore, I added the song to the post via Spotify. The chances of a given song being up on Spotify in a few years feels <em>marginally</em> higher than on Youtube right now. I had a few other embeds that I could fix with newer code (Soundcloud) and others that I couldn&rsquo;t (Deezer), but most of the time I could find the given song or playlist within Spotify. All of this had the benefit of walking down on memory lane, reading 10-year old blog posts and cringing a lot. <em>I was so young.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>I&rsquo;ve found a <a href="https://github.com/vinitkumar/white-paper">reasonably decent theme</a> for Jekyll, which felt like a good starting point, though it didn&rsquo;t have built-in support for tags or archives. I started googling how to implement that, and around the same time I was venting about my embed issues on the XOXO slack. That was when <a href="https://twitter.com/theory">David</a> chimed in about his experiences on doing this exact same process, except he ended up using <a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</a>, another popular static site generator that&rsquo;s kind of like Jekyll except faster. <a href="https://github.com/theory/justatheory/tree/master/themes/justatheory">The theme</a> of <a href="https://justatheory.com">his blog</a> had everything I wanted: a fancy archives page and proper support for tags. So I figured I might as well continue my journey: switch to Hugo and use his theme as a basis.</p>

<p>Jekyll is written in Ruby and uses a simple templating language. Hugo&rsquo;s code is in Go, and it uses Go&rsquo;s own templates; they definitely have a learning curve, even if you have coded in Go before. With some help, googling and a lot of trial and error, I got the hang of it and managed to change things to my liking as well as the look and the color scheme of the site. I converted most of my posts&rsquo; <a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/front-matter/">front matter</a> <a href="https://github.com/coderzh/ConvertToHugo">with a script</a> and fixed the rest with a few search-and-replaces. With 8-10 hours of work behind me — half of that was fixing those embeds — I had my new blog ready to be <a href="https://pages.github.com/">hosted on Github Pages for free</a>. I use a modified version of the <a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/#put-it-into-a-script-1">sample deploy script</a> they have in Hugo&rsquo;s documentation.</p>

<h3 id="getting-rid-of-my-vps">Getting Rid of My VPS</h3>

<p>I had a small VPS at Linode for years now, hosting my pet projects, my blog and a bunch of static sites (like my <a href="https://ktamas.com">home page</a>) over the years. It also had OpenVPN installed so I could watch iPlayer for free until BBC started cracking down on that. By now it only had my blog and those static sites; I figured if I could find something for the latter, I could ditch the VPS entirely.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t remember how, but I came across <a href="https://netlify.com">Netlify</a>. They give you free static hosting with extremely generous soft limits (100 gigs of storage, 100 GB/month transfer). You just point them to a Github repository, and about 30 seconds later you have your site ready, with support for multiple custom domains and SSL.</p>

<p>I spent an hour or two moving everything to Netlify, changing the necessary DNS entries and in the end, I was ready to say goodbye to my VPS and save a grand total of $7 a month in the future. I made backups of everything and then, somewhat emotionally pressed the &ldquo;Delete&rdquo; button on Linode&rsquo;s control panel. I wouldn&rsquo;t be surprised if I would get another one eventually for a side project or something, but for now, I&rsquo;m happy with my all my stuff hosted around the internet for free and stored in git repos.</p>

<h3 id="on-the-future-of-my-blog">On the Future of My Blog</h3>

<p>Making this move also means that I will start cross-posting my posts from <a href="https://writetogether.space/users/ktamas">WriteTogether</a> to here. One-off posts like this one will definitely make it here; the ongoing series I have at WriteTogether will probably stay there until they are done, and then I&rsquo;ll re-edit them into long-form posts and publish them here. I will also post content here that doesn&rsquo;t fit WriteTogether for one reason or another. Feel free to <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/KTamasBlog">subscribe to this blog</a> in your favorite RSS reader.</p>

<p>Hugo gives me a lot of ways to tinker; I am already thinking about replacing the commenting system, adding reading time, word count and so on. I might write something on this in again in the future.</p>

<p><em>This post was not sponsored by anyone, just in case some of it reads like an ad for Github or Netlify or whatever.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Converting My Blog To Hugo and Getting Rid of My VPS”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/01/converting-my-blog-to-hugo-and-getting-rid-of-my-vps/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/meta/'>meta</a>, <a href='/tags/tech/'>tech</a>, <a href='/tags/hugo/'>hugo</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/</id>
		<title>Musings on Turning 30</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-16T10:32:14Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-16T10:32:14Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="30" label="30"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>Ten years ago I was working at a translation agency, being very enthusiastic about my job. I just started having a social life again after high school, finding real-life friends and community on Early Twitter, thanks to a Twitter client that auto-aggregated Hungarian users and connected them. (That’s a story worth telling in itself, another time)
A lot has happened since then. I worked there for a few more years, then I moved to Sweden for four years and then moved back to Hungary.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Ten years ago I was working at a translation agency, being very enthusiastic about my job. I just started having a social life again after high school, finding real-life friends and community on Early Twitter, thanks to a Twitter client that auto-aggregated Hungarian users and connected them. (That&rsquo;s a story worth telling in itself, another time)</p>

<p>A lot has happened since then. I worked there for a few more years, then I moved to Sweden for four years and then moved back to Hungary. Somewhere in the middle of that, I went freelance, which overall turned out to be a huge success. I started taking care of my mental health, getting diagnosed and re-diagnosed, finding a psychiatrist, did almost six years of therapy. I traveled a lot; I&rsquo;ve been to most European countries by now as well as two trips to the US, both because of I got to be part of XOXO, but I&rsquo;ve visited other parts of the States as well. I did a small pivot in my career that so far worked out well. I lost two out of my four grandparents. <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/15/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community/">Built and ran a small link-sharing community</a>. Grown a lot personally and professionally. Discovered running, did that for a few years. Found and lost friends and communities.</p>

<hr />

<p>Right now I&rsquo;m in a pretty great place. I have well-paying clients and hopefully picking up more freelance work soon. I&rsquo;m part of a great church, one that I was looking for all my life. I have good friends, some old, some new. I&rsquo;ve started drawing a few months ago, and I enjoy it immensely. Yesterday, after years of procrastination, I finally found myself a personal trainer and will begin working with her next week. Although my sister is moving out of our place, a good friend is taking her place in the room next to mine. I&rsquo;m having a birthday party on Saturday where I&rsquo;ll cook for my friends. I feel at home where I am.</p>

<hr />

<p>Here&rsquo;s to an even better 40.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/musings-on-turning-30">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Musings on Turning 30”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/30/'>30</a>, <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/15/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community/</id>
		<title>In Memoriam of Sharewood — My Own Little Content Sharing Community</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/15/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-15T09:56:04Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-15T09:56:04Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="sharewood" label="sharewood"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="rss" label="rss"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="googlereader" label="googlereader"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>This post was inspired by the Motherboard article, The Rise and Demise of RSS.
It was early 2012 and Google Reader’s sharing function was taken from us, replaced with a useless, shitty “Share to Google+” button (Fuck you, Google). I’ve been using Reader since late 2005 and the sharing feature since it’s introduction; the notion that if I see something interesting on the internet I must share it with others was ingrained in me, forever.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>This post was inspired by the Motherboard article, <a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/a3mm4z/the-rise-and-demise-of-rss">The Rise and Demise of RSS</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>It was early 2012 and Google Reader&rsquo;s sharing function was taken from us, replaced with a useless, shitty &ldquo;Share to Google+&rdquo; button (Fuck you, Google). I&rsquo;ve been using Reader since late 2005 and the sharing feature since it&rsquo;s introduction; the notion that if I see something interesting on the internet <em>I must share it with others</em> was ingrained in me, forever.</p>

<p>It started with conversations with friends, and we discovered that Posterous (RIP) had a decent bookmarklet one could use to grab content for sharing. So a few of us started content-sharing blogs (or linkblogs, if you will). Not long after, a friend suggested an idea: why don&rsquo;t we make our own content-sharing community? So we could use that for a back-end, all we need is a place where we aggregate all these blogs full of content.</p>

<p>The name of software that is used to aggregate RSS feeds is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planet_(software)">Planet</a>. There were and still are many Planet sites, so I went looking for a suitable engine, but none of them were right until I stumbled upon the <a href="https://github.com/anildigital/planet">code</a> behind planetrubyonrails.com (RIP), written in, wait for it, Rails. I was already familiar with Rails, so <a href="https://github.com/ktamas/sharewood.hu">I forked it</a>, upgraded it to the latest version of Ruby on Rails, made a couple of changes and a basic design and by then I already had ten people interested, mostly from the old community at Reader.</p>

<p>A cronjob crawled the people&rsquo;s feeds, pulled the content into the database, stripped most of the formatting and then displayed it on the site, which itself had an RSS feed of course. And so, in early 2012, <a href="http://goodbye.sharewood.hu/">Sharewood</a> (RIP) was born.</p>

<hr />

<p>Over the next year or so our community has grown a bit. At the height of it, we had about 16 people. That may not sound like a lot, but a community is a community. People were sharing all kinds of interesting things, and I felt like I got back at least part of what we lost when Google neutered Reader.</p>

<p>The project was an opportunity for me as well to play with Rails; I ended up rewriting almost the entire codebase. I wrote a new RSS/Atom parser; tried to implement PuSH (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSub">PubSubHubBub</a>); added support for user accounts, so people would be able to follow others and get a custom RSS feed. I added a few tweaks to the front-end as well, like j/k navigation.</p>

<p>In early 2013 Google announced that they&rsquo;d shut down Reader and a flurry of new alternatives appeared. One of the most promising ones was Hivemined, one that would never be finished; the one I ended up switching to was <a href="https://newsblur.com/">NewsBlur</a> which I still use to this day. It&rsquo;s customizable, fast, has good support and UX. It also has built-in sharing and commenting support although it&rsquo;s not used widely. I tried switching to it, but never really got hooked on it, and I never had a community around it.</p>

<hr />

<p>I shut down Sharewood in 2014, having done only basic maintenance on it for a year by then, and I felt like it has run its course.</p>

<p>My itch to share things is still very much present; I <a href="http://sharing.ktamas.com/">maintain a Tumblr blog</a> where I share things irregularly, mostly webcomics I like. I also retweet interesting and funny things a lot <a href="https://twitter.com/ktamas">on Twitter</a>. But I still don&rsquo;t have a central place with a community like in the good old days, if you will.</p>

<p>I have no illusions; RSS will not make a comeback. Retweeting things and commenting on them or sharing things in private Slacks are as good as it gets right now.</p>

<p>The itch is still there.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on WriteTogether in <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community-part-1-of-2">two</a> <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community-part-2-of-2">parts</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “In Memoriam of Sharewood — My Own Little Content Sharing Community”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/15/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/sharewood/'>sharewood</a>, <a href='/tags/rss/'>rss</a>, <a href='/tags/googlereader/'>googlereader</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/06/see-you-at-write-together/</id>
		<title>Follow Me on WriteTogether</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/06/see-you-at-write-together/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-06T12:17:20Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-06T12:17:20Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I’ll be writing daily posts on Write Together for the foreseeable future. It’s a blogging platform/writing community with the goal of writing and publishing at least 300 words, every day. Most of them will be cross-posted here, but some I write as a series of posts, and those may be re-edited and published here once I’m done. If you’re interested, you should follow me there.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll be writing <a href="https://writetogether.space/users/ktamas">daily posts on Write Together</a> for the foreseeable future. It&rsquo;s a blogging platform/writing community with the goal of writing and publishing at least 300 words, every day. Most of them will be cross-posted here, but some I write as a series of posts, and those may be re-edited and published here once I&rsquo;m done. If you&rsquo;re interested, you should follow me there.</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Follow Me on WriteTogether”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/06/see-you-at-write-together/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/03/on-blogging-journaling-evernote-todos-and-thinking-in-weeks/</id>
		<title>On Blogging, Journaling, Evernote, Todos and Thinking in Weeks</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/03/on-blogging-journaling-evernote-todos-and-thinking-in-weeks/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-03T16:10:20Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-03T16:10:20Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="metablogging" label="metablogging"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="adhd" label="adhd"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>Well, it’s day 5 of my streak, and I have no idea what to write about. But they say you just have to start and eventually something will come out of it, so that’s what I am doing now.
Thing is, I have a blog, although I have not blogged regularly for years now. The only time I did that was in early 2013 when I moved to Sweden from Hungary.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Well, it&rsquo;s day 5 of my streak, and I have no idea what to write about. But they say you just have to start and eventually something will come out of it, so that&rsquo;s what I am doing now.</p>

<p>Thing is, <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">I have a blog</a>, although I have not blogged regularly for years now. The only time I did that was in early 2013 when I moved to Sweden from Hungary. For a while I did post daily because things were new and exciting, but eventually it just became regular life stuff, and I slowly stopped; other things became priority. Nevertheless, it was an important period in my life, and I&rsquo;m glad I have written memories of it.</p>

<p>Around 2013 I got myself a pocket-sized Moleskine, and I started writing down whatever came to my mind, journaling, more or less. I had that notebook with me religiously, in my right pocket, next to my wallet and in the next year and a half, I filled several of them. My favorite was the Evernote edition, which is not sold anymore. It gave you three months of Evernote premium but more importantly, it had nice, light, dot-grid pages which quickly became my favorite.</p>

<p>I kept writing in my notebooks until the start of 2015 when I went digital and started writing all the things down in Evernote. Now, Evernote is by no means a perfect app: it&rsquo;s bloated, slow and clumsy in many ways. And yet to this day, I have found no suitable replacement for it. It&rsquo;s one of those softwares that my brain got hardwired to (like OSX, or Lightroom). Plus it&rsquo;s available for every platform ever.</p>

<p>I usually make a note a day with the title being the current date. I make a lot of ad-hoc todo lists which is as close as I get to being organized with my todos, being tried at least a half dozen apps by now and never being able to stick to one.</p>

<p>(I still carry a paper notebook with me everywhere, an A5 dotted Leuchtturm1917 Bullet Journal that I use for regular notebook purposes because BuJoing turned out to be Not My Thing™, but they make good notebooks. I mostly use it to take notes when I&rsquo;m at my therapist.)</p>

<p>In the last few weeks, I&rsquo;m trying a new experiment with the todos, which is moving to a weekly format, so I have one Note with the todos for Week 51, one for Week 52 and so on. In each note, I have each day and a &ldquo;Later&rdquo; section, and I try to add as many things as possible because it gives me a sense of achievement and it&rsquo;s nice to look back on days when I thought I got nothing done.</p>

<p>P.S. Thinking in weeks is a very Swedish thing to do. In Sweden, everyone knows what week it is, and they frequently refer to them as in &ldquo;I&rsquo;m doing this on week X&rdquo; or &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll be on vacation between week Y and Z.&rdquo; If my memory serves me right, one of the most popular apps in the Swedish App Store for a long time was called &ldquo;Week Calendar&rdquo; until Apple added the option to display week numbers in Calendar. It drove me crazy for a long time, but I have to admit that it makes sense because it&rsquo;s a good unit of time. I&rsquo;ve been told the Germans do the same.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/on-blogging-journaling-evernote-todos-and-thinking-in-weeks">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “On Blogging, Journaling, Evernote, Todos and Thinking in Weeks”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/03/on-blogging-journaling-evernote-todos-and-thinking-in-weeks/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/metablogging/'>metablogging</a>, <a href='/tags/adhd/'>adhd</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/02/my-favorite-newsletters/</id>
		<title>My Favorite Newsletters</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/02/my-favorite-newsletters/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-02T16:07:02Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-02T16:07:02Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recommendations" label="recommendations"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="lists" label="lists"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>Newsletters are the new blogs, they say, and I hope not because I hate getting email. And yet there is ~content~ in newsletters, good content, so here’s a few that I subscribe to and like.
 Charged - I guess this one needs no introduction to this community ;) The week that was - Ian Kennedy’s once-a-week newsletter with usually ten links to interesting, unusual stories from all over the world.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Newsletters are the new blogs, they say, and I hope not because I hate getting email. And yet there is ~content~ in newsletters, good content, so here&rsquo;s a few that I subscribe to and like.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://char.gd">Charged</a> - I guess this one needs no introduction to this community ;)</li>
<li><a href="http://tinyletter.com/iankennedy">The week that was</a> - <a href="https://twitter.com/iankennedy">Ian Kennedy</a>&rsquo;s once-a-week newsletter with usually ten links to interesting, unusual stories from all over the world. Anything from someone <a href="https://www.thespec.com/whatson-story/9079216-price-is-right-contestant-wins-winter-trip-to-winnipeg/">winning a vacation to Winnipeg, Canada</a> to <a href="http://mail01.tinyletterapp.com/iankennedy/the-week-that-was-31/13264373-www.sfchronicle.com/bayarea/article/city-requires-property-owner-who-demolished-13467909.php?c=aab663ab-1d04-4dad-83bc-9281105551c5">punishing a San Francisco developer&rsquo;s illegal demolition by forcing the guy to rebuild the exact replica of the building</a>. [<a href="https://tinyletter.com/iankennedy/archive">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="http://jennyshen.com/newsletter/">Jenny Shen&rsquo;s newsletter</a> - I met <a href="https://twitter.com/jennyshen">Jenny</a> (and <a href="https://soundcloud.com/ktamasenty/untitled-podcast-episode-1-xoxo-recap">recorded a podcast with her</a>!) at XOXO 2018. She writes about design, her life, being a PoC in technology and everything in-between.</li>
<li><a href="https://tumblr.us12.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=8014320de9941eaab79e8a1ce&amp;id=a6274aff24">Laura Olin</a> - Another XOXO alum, sending out interesting things from all over the internet once a week. She has an interesting perspective on things. She also has a list of job opportunities in the media at the end of every newsletter.
[<a href="https://us12.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=8014320de9941eaab79e8a1ce&amp;id=a6274aff24">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://nicole.substack.com/">Nicole Knows</a> - This is <a href="http://the-toast.net/">The Toast</a> alum <a href="http://twitter.com/nicole_cliffe">Nicole Cliffe</a>&rsquo;s newsletter, do yourself a favor and follow her on twitter immediately as well. It&rsquo;s a mix of fun and weird Reddit threads and skincare. [<a href="https://nicole.substack.com/">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://nextdraft.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=ed102783e87fee61c1a534a9d&amp;id=dd6d48f649">NextDraft</a> - A daily newsletter from <a href="https://twitter.com/davepell">Dave Pell</a>, managing editor of the Internet. A mix of US politics and interesting random things. [<a href="https://us2.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=ed102783e87fee61c1a534a9d&amp;id=dd6d48f649">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://tinyletter.com/danhon">Things That Have Caught My Attention</a> - by <a href="http://twitter.com/hondanhon">Dan Hon</a>. An irregular newsletter with Dan&rsquo;s thoughts on a variety of issues, and the occasional weird fiction. It&rsquo;s long, but it&rsquo;s worth reading.  [<a href="https://tinyletter.com/danhon/archive">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://www.shatnerchatner.com/">The Shatner Chatner</a> - By <a href="http://the-toast.net/">The Toast</a> (and XOXO) alum <a href="https://twitter.com/danielortberg">Daniel Mallory Ortberg</a>. A mix of fiction and just plain weird but fun stuff. [<a href="https://www.shatnerchatner.com/">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://aarongilmore.us5.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9ddd4dee57ef929930b1a90b4&amp;id=8e47b7eb4a">The Web Is OK</a> - By <a href="https://twitter.com/aarondgilmore">Aaron Gilmore</a>, XOXO alum, coming in your inbox once a few with a few interesting stories from the web. [<a href="https://us5.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=9ddd4dee57ef929930b1a90b4&amp;id=8e47b7eb4a">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://us14.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=7d9a179d9349586da8d1fd80f&amp;id=47c259ca85">Leah Finnegan&rsquo;s newsletter</a> - <a href="https://twitter.com/leahfinnegan">Leah</a>, from <a href="https://theoutline.com">The Outline</a> writes mostly personal essays, and they are all pretty great. Check out her <a href="https://mailchi.mp/theoutline/how-to-kill-your-envy?e=ec4ceb0247">latest one about Envy</a>. [<a href="https://us14.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=7d9a179d9349586da8d1fd80f&amp;id=47c259ca85">archives</a>]</li>
<li><a href="https://jennmoney.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f74a824f6424f5f5819ec0f77&amp;id=738ef47ea4">Jenn Schiffer&rsquo;s newsletter</a> - Last but not least, <a href="https://twitter.com/jennschiffer">Jenn Schiffer</a>&rsquo;s newsletter never disappoints. Hard to put it in a box. It&rsquo;s wacky, and it&rsquo;s fun.
[<a href="https://us8.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=f74a824f6424f5f5819ec0f77&amp;id=738ef47ea4">archives</a>]</li>
</ul>

<p>What are yours?</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/my-favorite-newsletters">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “My Favorite Newsletters”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/02/my-favorite-newsletters/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/recommendations/'>recommendations</a>, <a href='/tags/lists/'>lists</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/01/a-year-in-smartphones/</id>
		<title>A Year in Smartphones</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/01/a-year-in-smartphones/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-01T16:00:02Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-01T16:00:02Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="tech" label="tech"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="phones" label="phones"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I started 2018 with wanting to try Android after not using it for like five years; I had a Nexus S with Android 4 point something back in 2013 before jumping on to the iPhone bandwagon. So I got myself a cheap Moto G5 Plus just to play around with it, and to my surprise, I promptly fell in love with the whole thing.
Android has come a long way, and in many ways, it’s a better fit for me than iOS.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I started 2018 with wanting to try Android after not using it for like five years; I had a Nexus S with Android 4 point something back in 2013 before jumping on to the iPhone bandwagon. So I got myself a cheap Moto G5 Plus just to play around with it, and to my surprise, I promptly fell in love with the whole thing.</p>

<p>Android has come a long way, and in many ways, it&rsquo;s a better fit for me than iOS. I like the (relative) openness of it, the way it handles notifications, the ability to turn off animations (I hate UI animations with a passion), the customizability in general, better integration with Google and so on. The G5 Plus shipped with 7.0 Nougat, with the promise of an Oreo upgrade coming in late 2017, which arrived at the end of 2018 and made an otherwise fast phone somewhat slow. It ships with a vanilla version of Android, with a few enhancements from Motorola that are actually useful: a few gestures (for example, shake twice for flashlight) and a really good implementation of an active display (you can preview and even dismiss notifications from it very quickly). Oh and it had a great battery life.</p>

<p>The phone did have one major flaw: the camera sucks. It&rsquo;s&hellip; passable at best, but even with the best daylight conditions, pictures simple look off at best, because of Motorola applying some extremely aggressive sharpening. Low-light performance? What low-light performance?</p>

<p>So I replaced it with a Pixel 2 which, at the time had the best camera on the market (it still is one of the best ones) and it was pretty great, except the GPS in it was pretty shitty, and I was used to using my phones for running. After it spending literally months in repair &ndash; which is hard in a country where you can only buy grey market imports; mine is from Canada &ndash;, going back and forth and getting nowhere, I just got fed up with the whole thing and sold it. Only later I learned that many of the high-end phones lately come with shitty GPSes and if you wanna go running, you better buy yourself a running watch.</p>

<p>In any case, I decided to jump back to iOS and got myself an iPhone X, about two months before the fall keynote. I figured I&rsquo;d replace it with the new model when it comes out but the XS is a ridiculously incremental upgrade and I have no desire whatsoever to spend money upgrading. Maybe next fall.</p>

<p>The X also has a good camera, and the optical 2x zoom should be mandatory on phones; its portrait mode is, in my experience, ever-so-slightly better than the Pixel 2&rsquo;s (its low light performance, on the other hand, is miles behind). I shot a <a href="http://facesofxoxo2018.tumblr.com">series of portraits with it on XOXO 2018</a>, and I was pretty satisfied with the results.</p>

<p>I do miss Android, but I came to appreciate the big screen in a relatively small package &ndash; I can still more or less use the X with one hand &ndash; as well as the build quality. iOS 12 was a very welcome update as well with a few small things (faster animations! less waiting!).</p>

<p>And there are certain things that, even in 2018 are just better in my experience on an iPhone; small things, like the smoothness of the touchscreen and the handle of touch in general, or having a working implementation of auto-brightness that not even the Pixel 2 can get right.</p>

<p>Overall I am pretty happy with the X, and I will stick with it for the foreseeable future, even though I recently got myself a Pixel 2 again because I needed an ARCore-capable phone for AR game development.</p>

<p>The moral of the story is that I have disposable income and I was bored. I am tempted to say that none of this stuff really matters but I spend a fair amount of time on my phone every day so&hellip; it kinda does for me.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/a-year-in-smartphones">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “A Year in Smartphones”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/01/a-year-in-smartphones/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/tech/'>tech</a>, <a href='/tags/phones/'>phones</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/</id>
		<title>My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="mediadiet" label="mediadiet"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I was planning to possibly dive into the YearCompass, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it’s not a great user experience.
I binged on the first season Condor yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I was planning to possibly dive into the <a href="https://yearcompass.com/">YearCompass</a>, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it&rsquo;s not a great user experience.</p>

<p>I binged on the first season <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condor_(TV_series)">Condor</a> yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller. I&rsquo;m looking forward to Season 2.</p>

<p>Before that, I watched the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impulse_(TV_series)">Impulse</a>, which is, uh, I guess inspired by one of my favorite Sci-fi books, but they only took the fundamental concept of the book and made into a pretty good teen drama, with this season focusing primarily on sexual assault and its effects.</p>

<p>I got a kick out of the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Succession_(TV_series)">Succession</a> which is cut from the &ldquo;despicable rich people prestige TV&rdquo; genre (see also: Billions). Pretty much everyone in it terrible in their own different entertaining ways, with no real heroes and yet you find yourself rooting for people.</p>

<p>Do yourself a simple favor and check out A Simple Favor (sorry) if you haven&rsquo;t seen it in the theaters: it was one of the most fun movies I saw in 2018. I hesitate to say anything about it as it is one of those movies that is best enjoyed going in knowing nothing about it; even stating its genre is a possible spoiler in my book, so you&rsquo;re just gonna have to trust me on that one.</p>

<p>Oh, and the Big Fat Quiz of The Year 2018 is out, which is an annual TV event of mostly British comedians being funny while pretending to play a quiz. It has two-thirds of The IT Crowd and also Michelle Wolf, among others.</p>

<p>Onwards to 2019!</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/mediadiet/'>mediadiet</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/</id>
		<title>A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recaps" label="recaps"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend’s idea I simply put out a “Hey, I’m looking for a cool team to work with” message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with… a cool team to work with.
Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend&rsquo;s idea I simply put out a &ldquo;Hey, I&rsquo;m looking for a cool team to work with&rdquo; message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with&hellip; a cool team to work with.</p>

<p>Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin. I&rsquo;m a generalist at heart but out of all the things I do, working with servers is probably my favorite bit and I feel privileged to do that once again.</p>

<p>I also continued to work with a few other clients on some ongoing projects, and I ended this year sending out a huge quote &ndash; one, if and if it works out, would keep me very busy in 2019, and that&rsquo;d be great, so crossing fingers on that.</p>

<p>On a more personal note, I tried University this year and while I had some small victories, I pretty much dropped out already &ndash; It&rsquo;s really not for me. And I knew that but I thought the prospect of having a degree and therefore better chances at immigration to the US would be motivating enough, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>This year I also started drawing and it&rsquo;s been fun! And I&rsquo;ve also been to XOXO 2018, which was probably even better than 2016 and Portland already feels like a second home for me.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t plan to travel a lot this year and yet I count 10 (wow) different trips abroad, and most of these were for fun. I&rsquo;ve been to Linz, Berlin, Gothenburg, Vienna, Amsterdam, San Francisco, Portland, Geneva, London.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really know yet what 2019 will bring. If the quote/job I mentioned above works out, I&rsquo;ll be very busy, and that&rsquo;s something I miss. If not&hellip; we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>Hey look, 300 words!</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/ktamas/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/recaps/'>recaps</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
