<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/thoughts/</id>
	<title>thoughts on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about thoughts</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-01-16T10:32:14Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/thoughts/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/thoughts/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.53">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/</id>
		<title>Musings on Turning 30</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-16T10:32:14Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-16T10:32:14Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="30" label="30"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>Ten years ago I was working at a translation agency, being very enthusiastic about my job. I just started having a social life again after high school, finding real-life friends and community on Early Twitter, thanks to a Twitter client that auto-aggregated Hungarian users and connected them. (That’s a story worth telling in itself, another time)
A lot has happened since then. I worked there for a few more years, then I moved to Sweden for four years and then moved back to Hungary.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Ten years ago I was working at a translation agency, being very enthusiastic about my job. I just started having a social life again after high school, finding real-life friends and community on Early Twitter, thanks to a Twitter client that auto-aggregated Hungarian users and connected them. (That&rsquo;s a story worth telling in itself, another time)</p>

<p>A lot has happened since then. I worked there for a few more years, then I moved to Sweden for four years and then moved back to Hungary. Somewhere in the middle of that, I went freelance, which overall turned out to be a huge success. I started taking care of my mental health, getting diagnosed and re-diagnosed, finding a psychiatrist, did almost six years of therapy. I traveled a lot; I&rsquo;ve been to most European countries by now as well as two trips to the US, both because of I got to be part of XOXO, but I&rsquo;ve visited other parts of the States as well. I did a small pivot in my career that so far worked out well. I lost two out of my four grandparents. <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/15/in-memoriam-of-sharewood-my-own-little-content-sharing-community/">Built and ran a small link-sharing community</a>. Grown a lot personally and professionally. Discovered running, did that for a few years. Found and lost friends and communities.</p>

<hr />

<p>Right now I&rsquo;m in a pretty great place. I have well-paying clients and hopefully picking up more freelance work soon. I&rsquo;m part of a great church, one that I was looking for all my life. I have good friends, some old, some new. I&rsquo;ve started drawing a few months ago, and I enjoy it immensely. Yesterday, after years of procrastination, I finally found myself a personal trainer and will begin working with her next week. Although my sister is moving out of our place, a good friend is taking her place in the room next to mine. I&rsquo;m having a birthday party on Saturday where I&rsquo;ll cook for my friends. I feel at home where I am.</p>

<hr />

<p>Here&rsquo;s to an even better 40.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/musings-on-turning-30">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Musings on Turning 30”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/16/musings-on-turning-30/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/30/'>30</a>, <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/</id>
		<title>My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="mediadiet" label="mediadiet"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I was planning to possibly dive into the YearCompass, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it’s not a great user experience.
I binged on the first season Condor yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I was planning to possibly dive into the <a href="https://yearcompass.com/">YearCompass</a>, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it&rsquo;s not a great user experience.</p>

<p>I binged on the first season <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condor_(TV_series)">Condor</a> yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller. I&rsquo;m looking forward to Season 2.</p>

<p>Before that, I watched the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impulse_(TV_series)">Impulse</a>, which is, uh, I guess inspired by one of my favorite Sci-fi books, but they only took the fundamental concept of the book and made into a pretty good teen drama, with this season focusing primarily on sexual assault and its effects.</p>

<p>I got a kick out of the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Succession_(TV_series)">Succession</a> which is cut from the &ldquo;despicable rich people prestige TV&rdquo; genre (see also: Billions). Pretty much everyone in it terrible in their own different entertaining ways, with no real heroes and yet you find yourself rooting for people.</p>

<p>Do yourself a simple favor and check out A Simple Favor (sorry) if you haven&rsquo;t seen it in the theaters: it was one of the most fun movies I saw in 2018. I hesitate to say anything about it as it is one of those movies that is best enjoyed going in knowing nothing about it; even stating its genre is a possible spoiler in my book, so you&rsquo;re just gonna have to trust me on that one.</p>

<p>Oh, and the Big Fat Quiz of The Year 2018 is out, which is an annual TV event of mostly British comedians being funny while pretending to play a quiz. It has two-thirds of The IT Crowd and also Michelle Wolf, among others.</p>

<p>Onwards to 2019!</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/mediadiet/'>mediadiet</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/</id>
		<title>A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recaps" label="recaps"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend’s idea I simply put out a “Hey, I’m looking for a cool team to work with” message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with… a cool team to work with.
Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend&rsquo;s idea I simply put out a &ldquo;Hey, I&rsquo;m looking for a cool team to work with&rdquo; message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with&hellip; a cool team to work with.</p>

<p>Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin. I&rsquo;m a generalist at heart but out of all the things I do, working with servers is probably my favorite bit and I feel privileged to do that once again.</p>

<p>I also continued to work with a few other clients on some ongoing projects, and I ended this year sending out a huge quote &ndash; one, if and if it works out, would keep me very busy in 2019, and that&rsquo;d be great, so crossing fingers on that.</p>

<p>On a more personal note, I tried University this year and while I had some small victories, I pretty much dropped out already &ndash; It&rsquo;s really not for me. And I knew that but I thought the prospect of having a degree and therefore better chances at immigration to the US would be motivating enough, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>This year I also started drawing and it&rsquo;s been fun! And I&rsquo;ve also been to XOXO 2018, which was probably even better than 2016 and Portland already feels like a second home for me.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t plan to travel a lot this year and yet I count 10 (wow) different trips abroad, and most of these were for fun. I&rsquo;ve been to Linz, Berlin, Gothenburg, Vienna, Amsterdam, San Francisco, Portland, Geneva, London.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really know yet what 2019 will bring. If the quote/job I mentioned above works out, I&rsquo;ll be very busy, and that&rsquo;s something I miss. If not&hellip; we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>Hey look, 300 words!</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/ktamas/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/recaps/'>recaps</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
