<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/mediadiet/</id>
	<title>mediadiet on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about mediadiet</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-02-16T08:26:17Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/mediadiet/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/mediadiet/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.54.0">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/16/my-recent-media-diet-february-2019/</id>
		<title>My Recent Media Diet (February, 2019)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/16/my-recent-media-diet-february-2019/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-16T08:26:17Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-16T08:26:17Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="mediadiet" label="mediadiet"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recommendations" label="recommendations"/>
		<summary>Here’s a bunch of television I’ve been enjoying recently.
Russian Doll: This was the highlight of recent times: 8 episodes of pure fun, with a proper ending. It’s best watched not knowing anything about it but here are the first five minutes: Nadia leaves her birthday party, and on the way home gets hit by a taxi, and dies. The next moment Nadia is back where the episode started, alive and well, on her own birthday party.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a bunch of television I&rsquo;ve been enjoying recently.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80211627">Russian Doll</a>:</strong> This was the highlight of recent times: 8 episodes of pure fun, with a proper ending. It&rsquo;s best watched not knowing anything about it but here are the first five minutes: Nadia leaves her birthday party, and on the way home gets hit by a taxi, and dies. The next moment Nadia is back where the episode started, alive and well, on her own birthday party. It&rsquo;s up on Netflix.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Star_Trek_Discovery_title_card.jpg">Star Trek: Discovery (Season 2)</a>:</strong> I&rsquo;ve only seen three episodes of the new season so far but all of them have been great and I very much like this new take on Star Trek. The fact that it&rsquo;s a prequel to The Original Series bothers me, though, because they could have had a lot more creative freedom and do less retconning if it would be set in another universe. It&rsquo;s also up on Netflix or CBS All Access if you&rsquo;re in the US.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanna_(TV_series)">Hanna (pilot)</a></strong>: This is based on the excellent <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0993842/">movie of the same name</a>. Hanna is raised in the forest by his father in isolation, training her to be self-sufficient and strong, because someone in the CIA is hunting them for Reasons we don&rsquo;t know yet. The pilot shows a lot of promise, but we&rsquo;ll have to wait until March to see the rest. It&rsquo;s up on Amazon Prime Video.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strike_Back_(TV_series)">Strike Back (Season 5)</a></strong>: A big, dumb action series about Section 20, a black ops group of MI6, saving the world, or at least parts of it. The writers&rsquo; contract mandated at least two machine-gun fights per episode. It&rsquo;s&hellip; okay at best, I won&rsquo;t be watching Season 6.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Counterpart_(TV_series)">Counterpart (Season 2)</a></strong>: Just before the end of the Cold War, scientists in East Germany discovered a parallel universe, a clone of theirs. In present day, Howard is working as a low-level bureucrat at the UN, overseeing the connection between those worlds, too low on the food chain to know what his actual work is about. Until one day, his &ldquo;other&rdquo; shows up, demanding to speak with him&hellip;<br />
Season 2 has one episode left but so far the series shows no signs of getting boring or tired. Highly recommended.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Good_Place">The Good Place (Season 3)</a></strong>: This has been quite a ride, huh? The first part of the season is a bit disorganized but it gets better as they go along and boy did they put on hell of a season finale. Can&rsquo;t wait for Season 4. If you haven&rsquo;t seen this series, check it out and don&rsquo;t read anything about it, because spoilers can ruin at least half the fun. Should be up on Netflix in Europe.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Punisher_(TV_series)">The Punisher (Season 2)</a></strong>: I loved the first season, but I quit this season after four episodes. The antagonist of Season 2 is just really, really bad. If you can get past that, it&rsquo;s on Netflix.</p>

<p>What have you been watching lately?</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “My Recent Media Diet (February, 2019)”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/16/my-recent-media-diet-february-2019/">My Recent Media Diet (February, 2019)</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/mediadiet/'>mediadiet</a>, <a href='/tags/recommendations/'>recommendations</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/</id>
		<title>My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-31T13:18:41Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="mediadiet" label="mediadiet"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recommendations" label="recommendations"/>
		<summary>I was planning to possibly dive into the YearCompass, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it’s not a great user experience.
I binged on the first season Condor yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I was planning to possibly dive into the <a href="https://yearcompass.com/">YearCompass</a>, I even put it on my todo list to print it out and take it with me to my favorite coffee shop, but I forgot to look at my todo list. Ah, the joys of ADHD. They do have a PDF that you can do electronically, but it&rsquo;s not a great user experience.</p>

<p>I binged on the first season <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condor_(TV_series)">Condor</a> yesterday, and I have to say it was a pretty fun spy thriller. I&rsquo;m looking forward to Season 2.</p>

<p>Before that, I watched the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impulse_(TV_series)">Impulse</a>, which is, uh, I guess inspired by one of my favorite Sci-fi books, but they only took the fundamental concept of the book and made into a pretty good teen drama, with this season focusing primarily on sexual assault and its effects.</p>

<p>I got a kick out of the first season of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Succession_(TV_series)">Succession</a> which is cut from the &ldquo;despicable rich people prestige TV&rdquo; genre (see also: Billions). Pretty much everyone in it terrible in their own different entertaining ways, with no real heroes and yet you find yourself rooting for people.</p>

<p>Do yourself a simple favor and check out A Simple Favor (sorry) if you haven&rsquo;t seen it in the theaters: it was one of the most fun movies I saw in 2018. I hesitate to say anything about it as it is one of those movies that is best enjoyed going in knowing nothing about it; even stating its genre is a possible spoiler in my book, so you&rsquo;re just gonna have to trust me on that one.</p>

<p>Oh, and the Big Fat Quiz of The Year 2018 is out, which is an annual TV event of mostly British comedians being funny while pretending to play a quiz. It has two-thirds of The IT Crowd and also Michelle Wolf, among others.</p>

<p>Onwards to 2019!</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/31/my-recent-media-diet-on-the-last-days-of-2018/">My Recent Media Diet in the Last Days of 2018</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/mediadiet/'>mediadiet</a>, <a href='/tags/recommendations/'>recommendations</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
