<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/archive/</id>
	<title>Previously, on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>Bringing you irregular content since 2009. By KTamas.</subtitle>
	<updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/archive/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/archive/"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="application/json" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/archive/feed.json"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.66.0">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/03/11/how-to-stay-sane-on-twitter-dot-com/</id>
		<title>How to Stay Sane on Twitter</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/03/11/how-to-stay-sane-on-twitter-dot-com/"/>
		<updated>2020-03-11T12:41:30Z</updated>
		<published>2020-03-11T12:41:30Z</published>
		<summary>If you’re like me, you probably spend a lot of time on Twitter. I don’t blame nor judge you for that — it’s a simple fact of life. However, if you’re reading this, you are also aware that it can be overwhelming and anxiety-inducing at times, what with everyone being on edge for, ah, many reasons these days.
Sure, you could just spend less time on the hellsite, but we both know that’s not going to happen.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/01/06/sarah-kay-dreaming-boy/</id>
		<title>Sarah Kay - Dreaming Boy</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/01/06/sarah-kay-dreaming-boy/"/>
		<updated>2020-01-06T10:48:07Z</updated>
		<published>2020-01-06T10:48:07Z</published>
		<summary>(I haven’t found a page with both the video and the text where it was formatted what looks like how it was likely intended so I made my own. Source for the text is here.)
 In most of the dreams I remember
from childhood, I am a boy. Saving a maiden
or not saving anyone in particular, but definitely a boy.
For years, when the only language I had were the scraps</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/01/01/all-the-podcasts-im-listening-to-right-now/</id>
		<title>All the Podcasts I&#39;m Listening to Right Now</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2020/01/01/all-the-podcasts-im-listening-to-right-now/"/>
		<updated>2020-01-01T20:15:30Z</updated>
		<published>2020-01-01T20:15:30Z</published>
		<summary>I’ve had friends over two days ago and we got to talk about podcasts, so I figured I’d take stock and see what I’m listening to these days. I’m subscribed to 98 podcasts in PocketCasts, but the ones that are in active rotation are a fraction of that. I usually listen to podcasts when I went to bed because I need some sort of noise to fall asleep more often than not.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/12/19/star-wars-9/</id>
		<title>Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker review (with spoilers)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/12/19/star-wars-9/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-19T12:48:05Z</updated>
		<published>2019-12-19T12:48:05Z</published>
		<summary>*** SPOILERS BELOW *** .
.
.
.
.
*taps mic*
*takes a deep breath*
GODDAMMIT JJ I AM A 100% FINE WITH YOU MAKING TWO HOURS OF FANSERVICE BUT THEN FUCKING COMMIT TO IT
*rubs temples*
Now that the new trilogy is complete, it makes me reevaluate the previous movies. The Force Awakens was pure fanservice; didn’t innovate much, stuck to well-known tropes, and yet it was heaps of fun.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/17/xoxo-2019-closing-thoughts-and-gratitude/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Closing Thoughts and #gratitude</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/17/xoxo-2019-closing-thoughts-and-gratitude/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-17T08:26:11Z</updated>
		<published>2019-10-17T08:26:11Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday, Part 4 - Thursday, Part 5 - Friday, Part 6 - Saturday, Part 7 - Sunday, Part 8 - Monday (after))
As I mentioned in the very first post, XOXO caught me at a particularly vulnerable and bad time, mental health-wise. Despite that, I had an overall amazing time at XOXO and for most of it, I managed to forget at least some of my worries and focus on spending time with all the amazing people in this community.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/16/xoxo-2019-part-8/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 8 - Monday (after)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/16/xoxo-2019-part-8/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-16T08:25:56Z</updated>
		<published>2019-10-16T08:25:56Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday, Part 4 - Thursday, Part 5 - Friday, Part 6 - Saturday, Part 7 - Sunday)
I woke up way too early, around 7:30 and checked the Slack as the previous night there were talks of having breakfast together with the people who were still in town. After returning the coats I got from Pendelton, I made my way to La Luna Cafe where we basically took over the whole place.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/15/xoxo-2019-part-7/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019 Part 7 - Sunday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/15/xoxo-2019-part-7/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-15T10:25:50Z</updated>
		<published>2019-10-15T10:25:50Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday, Part 4 - Thursday, Part 5 - Friday, Part 6 - Saturday)
After getting to bed so late, I decided to sleep in, so I set an alarm for 10:45 am. The last few days have been eventful, and I was started getting sad about it being the last day of XOXO.
I got to Rev Hall short after 11.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/14/xoxo-2019-part-6/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 6 - Saturday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/10/14/xoxo-2019-part-6/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-14T10:25:45Z</updated>
		<published>2019-10-14T10:25:45Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday, Part 4 - Thursday, Part 5 - Friday)
I woke up around 8:30 to a horrible nightmare, in which I was banned from XOXO because I tried to sneak someone I know in who’s an asshole. On the way to Rev Hall, I took a duckface selfie for Jan, who couldn’t come this year.
I got to the venue around 9:30 and got breakfast once again at Fried Egg I’m in Love.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/30/xoxo-2019-part-5/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 5 - Friday (Social)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/30/xoxo-2019-part-5/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-30T10:39:07Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-30T10:39:07Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday, Part 4 - Thursday)
Friday was Social, which is probably my favorite day and the highlight of XOXO, with all the community-organized events.
I got to Rev Hall early so I got my daily writing done, then went to a cafe nearby for the off-the-books #ptsd channel meetup. I was on the fence about going but I’m really glad I did; it was one of the best ones I’ve attended.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/29/xoxo-2019-part-4/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 4 - Thursday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/29/xoxo-2019-part-4/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-29T10:45:02Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-29T10:45:02Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday, Part 3 - Wednesday)
The excitement from the previous night lasted till the next morning as I woke up way too early, around 6 am. I had a Skype session with my therapist, then went to the La Luna Cafe for breakfast. The past week or so, I kept inviting XOXO friends, both old and new for a pre-registration breakfast. A lot of them came: Dan, Emory, Eliza, Georgie, her husband Nick, her friend Kylie, Andrew, Jim, Ben, Joel, Tiffany and I might be forgetting people.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/28/xoxo-2019-part-3/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 3 - Wednesday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/28/xoxo-2019-part-3/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-28T11:37:44Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-28T11:37:44Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday, Part 2 - Tuesday)
I’ve had an idea for a T-shirt for years, and the week before XOXO I finally acted on it. I wanted to have a T-shirt with “Helvetica” in big, bold letters. Here, this is how it looks like:
It’s cool, right? At first, it’s nothing special. It’s just “Helvetica” in Helvetica. Right?
There, I zoomed in a bit. Can you see it yet?</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/27/xoxo-2019-part-2/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 2 - Tuesday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/27/xoxo-2019-part-2/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-27T08:06:07Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-27T08:06:07Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue, Part 1 - Monday)
Look, I know that Scooters Are Bad, but the thing is, they are also really fun. So I put up with the minuscule amount of guilt I had about that and decided to use scooters as much as possible during my stay in Portland. And on Tuesday, I devised myself a challenge.
I was going to hang out with Josh and Angela at their place (and then visit a few other spots.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/26/xoxo-2019-part-1/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Part 1 - Monday</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/26/xoxo-2019-part-1/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-26T10:12:05Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-26T10:12:05Z</published>
		<summary>(Previously: Prologue)
I arrived at Portland on Labor Day. I intended to spend as much time in Portland as possible (and financially viable.) I knew from experience that even before the opening party on Thursday, there could be plenty of opportunities to hang out with people. Folks who live in Portland and others who also get in town a few days before.
One of the advantages of flying in from Canada is you get past CBP early, on the Canadian side: once you land in the US, you go directly to picking up your suitcases.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/25/xoxo-2019-prologue/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2019: Prologue</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/09/25/xoxo-2019-prologue/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-25T16:40:29Z</updated>
		<published>2019-09-25T16:40:29Z</published>
		<summary>A friend told me a few years before, that “XOXO is a place full of people you want to hang out with all the time,” and boy was he right. In 2016, I got to attend the first time, and I was hooked and had a blast. Two years later I was back (I have yet to write that one up), and it was a different experience: so much has happened in those two years.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/08/14/xoxo-2016/</id>
		<title>XOXO 2016 recap</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/08/14/xoxo-2016/"/>
		<updated>2019-08-14T09:12:43Z</updated>
		<published>2019-08-14T09:12:43Z</published>
		<summary>Table of Contents  What is XOXO? Beginnings — Before the Festival Tuesday — A Surprise Dinner Wednesday — The Day Before Thursday — MeFi Meetup, Opening Party Friday — Social, Arcade, Story Saturday — Conference, Day 1 + Film Sunday — Conference, Day 2 Monday — Post-Festival Pancakes Reflections  
What is XOXO? Not everyone reading this knows what XOXO is or how it works, so I’m going to start this series with an overview.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/17/travel-plans-and-dreams-for-2019/</id>
		<title>Travel Plans and Dreams for 2019</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/17/travel-plans-and-dreams-for-2019/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-17T13:14:58Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-17T13:14:58Z</published>
		<summary>My sister came over last night, and we had a good time. We cooked what we pretty much always cook — fajitas — and watched a movie, as well as started planning a short summer trip to Estonia and Finland. I’ve been there, but she hasn’t, and I like both places, so I’m happy to go with her and show my favorite places there, as well as explore new ones. Right now the plan is to spend a day in Tallinn, at least a day and a half in a nearby national park, then take the ferry to Helsinki and visit the woods near Espoo before heading home.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/16/my-recent-media-diet-february-2019/</id>
		<title>My Recent Media Diet (February, 2019)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/16/my-recent-media-diet-february-2019/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-16T08:26:17Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-16T08:26:17Z</published>
		<summary>Here’s a bunch of television I’ve been enjoying recently.
Russian Doll: This was the highlight of recent times: 8 episodes of pure fun, with a proper ending. It’s best watched not knowing anything about it but here are the first five minutes: Nadia leaves her birthday party, and on the way home gets hit by a taxi, and dies. The next moment Nadia is back where the episode started, alive and well, on her own birthday party.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/15/on-yoga/</id>
		<title>On Yoga</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/15/on-yoga/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-15T12:02:59Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-15T12:02:59Z</published>
		<summary>I’ve written about my relationship with exercise, but I left out a significant bit: yoga.
Growing up fundamentalist, you learn that yoga (and most martial arts) are Bad. It’s by the devil; you’re worshiping other Gods, and so on. Even though I’ve been working hard to get rid of these parts of my faith, it’s a slow and arduous process.
So I never even thought of trying it for a long time.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/14/on-excercise/</id>
		<title>On Exercise</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/14/on-excercise/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-14T10:02:11Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-14T10:02:11Z</published>
		<summary>Facts Let’s start with a few facts. I’m fat. I’m 174 (5’7”) and I weight about 125 kilos (275 pounds). I’ve had high blood pressure for the last 15 years or so, though the causes of that are complex. My cholesterol is officially considered high as of a few months ago, and if I don’t do something about it, I’ll have to start taking meds for it.
A huge part of it is likely genetics; men on my father’s side are historically overweight.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/13/on-photography/</id>
		<title>On Photography</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/13/on-photography/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-13T09:24:53Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-13T09:24:53Z</published>
		<summary>My father is a semi-amateur photographer; I got my affinity towards photography from him. I grew up watching him taking pictures. After high school, I got a job and soon I had disposable income, so I got my first digital camera: the Olympus E-1.
That was in 2008, and by then, it was already outdated. Released in 2003, it had a first-generation micro 4/3 sensor, 5 megapixels and ISO 800 was barely usable.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/12/on-living-alone-living-with-flatmates-and-having-the-best-apartment/</id>
		<title>On Living Alone, Living With Flatmates and Having the Best Apartment</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/12/on-living-alone-living-with-flatmates-and-having-the-best-apartment/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-12T13:23:02Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-12T13:23:02Z</published>
		<summary>I signed the new contract for my apartment a couple days ago. There has been a change: my youngest sister is moving in with her boyfriend, so one of my friends is taking her place.
I’ll miss my sister. We get along well and enjoy each other’s company. In practice, she’s been gone for more, than six months now: spending the majority of her time at her boyfriend’s place and coming home for only a couple days a month.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/09/on-board-games/</id>
		<title>On Board Games</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/09/on-board-games/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-09T16:07:47Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-09T16:07:47Z</published>
		<summary>I got sucked into “real” board games about a decade ago. Some of my newfound friends from Twitter were into them, so we got together one night and started playing Catan, the gateway drug to the board game world.
Catan isn’t bad, per se; it’s just there are so many games that are much better than it, so we moved on to other games. After my move to Sweden, for a couple of years, I didn’t have too many friends to play with.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/04/flow-on-remote-work-and-cafes/</id>
		<title>Flow (on Remote Work and Cafés)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/04/flow-on-remote-work-and-cafes/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-04T20:29:15Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-04T20:29:15Z</published>
		<summary>I’m a freelancer; I don’t have an office. I can’t work from home; the silence is deafening, I need the background noise, and I need to be among people. The place I work from every day is a café about 25 minutes from my home; it’s called Flow. I am a person of habit: I wake up, I get dressed, I go to Flow and start working.
Flow is one of the many, many specialty cafés in Budapest.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/03/on-drawing/</id>
		<title>On Drawing</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/03/on-drawing/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-03T22:05:46Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-03T22:05:46Z</published>
		<summary>I started University last fall, and I used that as an excuse to get a 2018 iPad and an Apple Pencil. I had to take notes, after all, and why not do it digitally? The university thing didn’t last, but something else happened after a month or so: I started drawing.
 I wasn’t that into drawing as a kid. Sure, I doodled just like everyone else, especially at a young age, and I do remember doing at least one pastel drawing, but that was about it.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/02/i-am-not-sponsored-by-grammarly-but-at-this-point-i-really-should-be/</id>
		<title>I Am Not Sponsored by Grammarly but at This Point I Really Should Be</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/02/i-am-not-sponsored-by-grammarly-but-at-this-point-i-really-should-be/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-02T22:07:51Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-02T22:07:51Z</published>
		<summary>I was going to finally get back to work on my latest series before I distracted myself with other things, like tweaking my blog (word counts! reading time! endlessly tweaking the CSS!) as well as continuing to cross-post some of my writings from here. One thing I noticed is how my writing has improved over the last month (at least in my opinion). I was also mildly horrified how bad my spelling and grammar was before I started using Grammarly.</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>

