<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/yoga/</id>
	<title>yoga on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about yoga</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-02-15T12:02:59Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/yoga/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/yoga/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.54.0">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/15/on-yoga/</id>
		<title>On Yoga</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/15/on-yoga/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-15T12:02:59Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-15T12:02:59Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="exercise" label="exercise"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="yoga" label="yoga"/>
		<summary>I’ve written about my relationship with exercise, but I left out a significant bit: yoga.
Growing up fundamentalist, you learn that yoga (and most martial arts) are Bad. It’s by the devil; you’re worshiping other Gods, and so on. Even though I’ve been working hard to get rid of these parts of my faith, it’s a slow and arduous process.
So I never even thought of trying it for a long time.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/14/on-excercise/">written about</a> my relationship with exercise, but I left out a significant bit: yoga.</p>

<p>Growing up fundamentalist, you learn that yoga (and most martial arts) are <em>Bad</em>. It&rsquo;s by the devil; you&rsquo;re worshiping other Gods, and so on. Even though I&rsquo;ve been working hard to get rid of these parts of my faith, it&rsquo;s a slow and arduous process.</p>

<p>So I never even thought of trying it for a long time. Then a former coworker and friend got into it; time to time she&rsquo;d say &ldquo;You should really give yoga a try,&rdquo; and I would be like yeah, maybe, someday. Putting aside old and harmful beliefs, it also looked just&hellip; boring.</p>

<hr />

<p>In late 2014 I broke my leg. Recovery was slow and painful, even though I did a decent amount of physical therapy. One day I stumbled upon a mass yoga event on Facebook and for whatever reason, I thought &ldquo;eh, okay, why not?&rdquo; So I went. It was awkward, unusual and weird, but I distinctly remember that afterwards the pain from my leg just disappeared for two days, like a miracle.</p>

<p>Even that was not enough at the time to start a regular practice, but in the spring of 2016, I finally pulled the trigger. I didn&rsquo;t even know how to breathe right on the first class (hint: use only your nose), but it felt amazing, especially after the class. So I kept going back, as much as I could, though I was traveling a lot during that time.</p>

<p>Yoga made me at least a bit more flexible, but more importantly, it helped me to slow down, and it gave me space to process things. My mind would often wander during class, and while that&rsquo;s somewhat discouraged, it was exactly what I needed at that time. And more often than not I would leave calmer and feeling more at peace with myself, something I desperately needed.</p>

<p>I was spoiled by having a great class filled with other expats and <a href="http://www.unfoldyourmat.com/">my awesome teacher, Lavinia</a>. For her regular drop-in classes I&rsquo;ve visited, she has her own style, a mix of existing ones, that has evolved over the recent years.</p>

<p><center><img src="https://i.imgur.com/mVKUk8V.jpg" alt="Lavinia and I" />  </center>
<center>Me and my teacher</center></p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t done much yoga since I left Sweden. I&rsquo;ve searched and tried, but I haven&rsquo;t found a good class/teacher that I was happy with long-term—like I said, I was really spoiled, and it set the bar high. And maybe it&rsquo;s not what I need right now.</p>

<p>To this day though, whenever I visit Gothenburg, I make it a point to go to at least one of her classes, and they never fail to disappoint me. In an ideal world, I would be able to teleport to Sweden once a week for a 90-minute class.</p>

<p>I can only tell you what my friend kept telling me: you should really give yoga a try.</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “On Yoga”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/15/on-yoga/">On Yoga</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/exercise/'>exercise</a>, <a href='/tags/yoga/'>yoga</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
