<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/milestones/</id>
	<title>milestones on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about milestones</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-01-29T16:38:36Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/milestones/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/milestones/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.58.3">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/29/on-writing-for-31-days-straight-and-counting/</id>
		<title>On Writing for 31 Days Straight and Counting</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/29/on-writing-for-31-days-straight-and-counting/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-29T16:38:36Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-29T16:38:36Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="milestones" label="milestones"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="meta" label="meta"/>
		<summary>Last night I went to bed feeling I might be getting sick, and I woke up most definitely sick. It feels like something in-between a cold and full-blown flu, and I mean, whatever, it’ll pass. What bothers me is the timing: I started working with a personal trainer last week and been to 4 classes so far. Now I’ll have to skip a bunch, and that’s bad when you are building a habit.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>Last night I went to bed feeling I might be getting sick, and I woke up most definitely sick. It feels like something in-between a cold and full-blown flu, and I mean, whatever, it&rsquo;ll pass. What bothers me is the timing: I started working with a personal trainer last week and been to 4 classes so far. Now I&rsquo;ll have to skip a bunch, and that&rsquo;s bad when you are building a habit.</p>

<p>I have at least one more post ready in my SF &amp; XOXO 2018 series (to come), but right now I&rsquo;m struggling to write end edit the ones that come after them. So I&rsquo;m taking a break today to reflect on writing, and in particular, writing here.</p>

<hr />

<p>This is my 31st post here, and I have not skipped a single day. I joined the day Owen opened signups. It&rsquo;s the second longest personal writing streak I have — the first one would be the one I did when I moved to Sweden and blogged about my life daily for the first few months. I&rsquo;m sure I skipped days here and there, but I wrote a lot during those days.</p>

<p>I used the term personal writing intentionally. Back in 2003, shortly after I started high school, I started working for a tech news site covering mobile devices, phones and PDAs.</p>

<p><em>(remember PDAs? I was</em> really <em>into them and had several over the years, even smartphones, and this was years before the iPhone. That&rsquo;s where most of the money I earned went.)</em></p>

<p>I kept track of what&rsquo;s up with the tech world and wrote a news article about whatever I&rsquo;ve found interesting and fit my scope. For the first two years or so I did it for free; after that, I earned roughly 75 cents per news article. I wrote a few features, reviews and interviews as well (can&rsquo;t remember how much I made from that, but not a lot).</p>

<p>In many ways, it was the dream writing job. I could write about anything I wanted, and the money I earned with it was significant for a 17-year old still living with their parents. I do feel somewhat ripped off financially in retrospect, though.</p>

<p>I stopped working for the site not long before I finished high school — I sort of lost interest. I think it had run its course.</p>

<p>Some habits do stay with me to this day from that era. Keeping up with the news is one of the reasons I got addicted to RSS and Google Reader. I read The Verge&rsquo;s and Ars Technica&rsquo;s feed religiously to this day, even though it is no longer necessary and I skip reading like 95% of it.</p>

<hr />

<p>All of the writing I mentioned above has been in Hungarian, though. This is the first time I am writing a significant amount in English, a language that&rsquo;s not my mother tongue. Now, I pride myself having a good grasp on the English language, and have been fluent in it since I was 15 or so. I don&rsquo;t even have the stereotypical Hungarian accent; it sounds like generic American English to most ears. When I lived in Sweden, I spoke English 90% of the time. I can and still do think in English a lot. When I&rsquo;m alone and am talking to myself, that&rsquo;s often in English as well.</p>

<p>And yet, writing is a different beast entirely. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;m bad at it, but I&rsquo;m conscious of the fact that I&rsquo;m not great either, and have a lot to learn. I run everything I write through Grammarly and Hemingway, and they help, but they&rsquo;re not silver bullets. I started reading <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0090RVGW0/">On Writing Well</a> (<a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/owen/the-tyranny-of-writing">thanks, Owen</a>), since nonfiction writing is my thing. And posting here at least 300 words every day itself helps a lot.</p>

<hr />

<p>So here I am, 31 days later; a month done, who knows how many to go. And I enjoy it a lot, even though I have no metrics on how many people are reading these posts of mine (I like having an audience and will not apologize for that). For now, I&rsquo;ll go back to editing and rewriting my series. I have work to do.</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “On Writing for 31 Days Straight and Counting”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/29/on-writing-for-31-days-straight-and-counting/">On Writing for 31 Days Straight and Counting</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/milestones/'>milestones</a>, <a href='/tags/meta/'>meta</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
