<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/drawing/</id>
	<title>drawing on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about drawing</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-02-03T22:05:46Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/drawing/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/drawing/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.56.3">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/03/on-drawing/</id>
		<title>On Drawing</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/03/on-drawing/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-03T22:05:46Z</updated>
		<published>2019-02-03T22:05:46Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="drawing" label="drawing"/>
		<summary>I started University last fall, and I used that as an excuse to get a 2018 iPad and an Apple Pencil. I had to take notes, after all, and why not do it digitally? The university thing didn’t last, but something else happened after a month or so: I started drawing.
I wasn’t that into drawing as a kid. Sure, I doodled just like everyone else, especially at a young age, and I do remember doing at least one pastel drawing, but that was about it.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I started University last fall, and I used that as an excuse to get a 2018 iPad and an Apple Pencil. I had to take notes, after all, and why not do it digitally? The university thing didn&rsquo;t last, but something else happened after a month or so: I started drawing.</p>

<hr />

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t that into drawing as a kid. Sure, I doodled just like everyone else, especially at a young age, and I do remember doing at least one pastel drawing, but that was about it. Hell, I was not much into visual arts either, or so it feels like, with the notable exception of photography. So it surprised even myself when one day, on a whim, I paid $10 for Procreate and promptly spent the next few days glued to my iPad and drawing every waking minute of the day.</p>

<p>A few months before that, <a href="https://facesofxoxo2018.tumblr.com/">I did a series of portraits</a> at XOXO 2018 and they felt like a natural starting point. I started tracing these photos; open them in Procreate, set the opacity to around 50% or so, create a new layer, pick up my virtual graphite pencil and start drawing over them. I think I did about a dozen of these; <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BonAsl3Ab18/">you</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BooYFCoAPIs/">can</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BorP2uBAfze/">find</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bot2On1iq3R/">some</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BoxAg_gChRj/">of</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BozvU_NAlbn/">them</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bo460bQAE0h/">on</a> <a href="https://instagram.com/ktamasenty">my Instagram</a>.  Looking at them months later, I think they don&rsquo;t look too bad for a newbie.</p>

<p>Tracing felt like cheating — even though I know it&rsquo;s not — and the next step was to find something or someone to draw.  I was already aware of a place in Budapest called <a href="https://www.painterspalace.eu/">Painters Palace</a>, a great art community that has weekly figure drawing classes. It&rsquo;s full of amazing people, and they have a fantastic space.</p>

<p>I fell in love with figure drawing the very first time I did it. Drawing the naked human body is may not be the easiest thing, but it&rsquo;s loads of fun. It didn&rsquo;t take me long before I started modeling as well; I did it twice so far, and I plan to do it more in the future. My Instagram has a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BpDQN_cAj0R/">few early drawings</a> posted, and I started posting my huge backlog to my <a href="https://www.instagram.com/ktamasart">art account</a>.</p>

<p>Another thing I started doing was drawing hands from reference images. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BtG1QNQj3JB/">I have</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BtI7WwyAdhj/">a couple</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BtL7W7EA7yn/">of these</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BtbDYBIgrmS/">published</a> so far with at least one more to come.</p>

<hr />

<p>There is some irony in the fact that even though I do almost all my drawing digitally, I use pencil and charcoal and I&rsquo;m consciously trying to make them look like analog drawings. That being said, I don&rsquo;t have much desire to use &ldquo;real&rdquo; pencil and paper, at least not right now.</p>

<p>All in all, it&rsquo;s a great outlet for creativity and I&rsquo;m very happy I discovered it.</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “On Drawing”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/02/03/on-drawing/">On Drawing</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/drawing/'>drawing</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
