<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writersblock/</id>
	<title>writersblock on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about writersblock</subtitle>
	<updated>2019-01-18T16:11:50Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writersblock/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/writersblock/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.54.0">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/18/writer-unblocked/</id>
		<title>Writer, Unblocked</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/18/writer-unblocked/"/>
		<updated>2019-01-18T16:11:50Z</updated>
		<published>2019-01-18T16:11:50Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writersblock" label="writersblock"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="writetogether" label="writetogether"/>
		<summary>I have no idea what to write today but I will start, and I am sure words will come.
I have a couple of topics floating in my head for longer stories. One is obviously continuing my memoir about my time in Sweden but I’ve hit a snag there: I got to the part where I arrived in Sweden, and now there are a couple of months where I am unsure what I should write about.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>I have no idea what to write today but I will start, and I am sure words will come.</p>

<p>I have a couple of topics floating in my head for longer stories. One is obviously continuing my memoir about my time in Sweden but I&rsquo;ve hit a snag there: I got to the part where I arrived in Sweden, and now there are a couple of months where I am unsure what I should write about. It&rsquo;ll come, though.</p>

<p>I have another thing to write about: the story of Turulcsirip, an early Hungarian Twitter community that was quite unique at the time. Part of me wants to make a real article of it, an oral history: interview the guy who created it, the earliest users, and so on. But I&rsquo;m not sure if that&rsquo;s a good fit for this platform. I can tell this story from just my perspective, and that would give you a somewhat good image of it as well, so I might just do that.</p>

<p>I am not yet sure if I want to write mostly multi-part stories (that you have to plan at least somewhat in advance) or more one-off things. For some reason, the former sounds easier for me, because if I just sit down to write <em>something</em>, I draw a blank. But that&rsquo;s something I want to improve as well.</p>

<p>Then again, I don&rsquo;t want to write just for writing&rsquo;s sake, only to have my streak, like I am doing right now. I want to write meaningful things, things people enjoy and find engaging. I feel like I have a lot of stories to tell; there is enough material. Now I just have to do the writing itself.</p>

<p>This whole post is just a shameless thing to get my streak, look, 300 words exactly.</p>

<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://writetogether.space/posts/5/writer-unblocked">WriteTogether</a>.</em></p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “Writer, Unblocked”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2019/01/18/writer-unblocked/">Content</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/writersblock/'>writersblock</a>, <a href='/tags/writetogether/'>writetogether</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
