<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
	<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/recaps/</id>
	<title>recaps on KTamas&#39; Blog</title>
	<subtitle>An ongoing list of KTamas' Blog posts about recaps</subtitle>
	<updated>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</updated>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/recaps/feed.xml"/>
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags/recaps/"/>
	<author>
		<name>KTamas</name>
		<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.56.3">Hugo</generator>
	<icon>"https://blog.ktamas.com/icon-512x512.png"</icon>
	<rights>© Tamas Kadar, 2009-2019. All Rights Reserved.</rights>
	<entry>
		<id>https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/</id>
		<title>A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/"/>
		<updated>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</updated>
		<published>2018-12-30T13:06:11Z</published>
		<author>
			<name>KTamas</name>
			<uri>https://blog.ktamas.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/>
		<category scheme="https://blog.ktamas.com/tags" term="recaps" label="recaps"/>
		<summary>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend’s idea I simply put out a “Hey, I’m looking for a cool team to work with” message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with… a cool team to work with.
Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin.</summary>
		<content type="text/html" xml:base="https://blog.ktamas.com/" xml:space="preserve" mode="xml">
<![CDATA[<p>2018 was a strange year for me. I started it out sort of aimless, not knowing what to do professionally. Then, stealing a friend&rsquo;s idea I simply put out a &ldquo;Hey, I&rsquo;m looking for a cool team to work with&rdquo; message to social media and got a ton of different offers and I ended up with&hellip; a cool team to work with.</p>

<p>Since February I have essentially a very well-paid half-time job at a small but important hosting company as a sysadmin. I&rsquo;m a generalist at heart but out of all the things I do, working with servers is probably my favorite bit and I feel privileged to do that once again.</p>

<p>I also continued to work with a few other clients on some ongoing projects, and I ended this year sending out a huge quote &ndash; one, if and if it works out, would keep me very busy in 2019, and that&rsquo;d be great, so crossing fingers on that.</p>

<p>On a more personal note, I tried University this year and while I had some small victories, I pretty much dropped out already &ndash; It&rsquo;s really not for me. And I knew that but I thought the prospect of having a degree and therefore better chances at immigration to the US would be motivating enough, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>This year I also started drawing and it&rsquo;s been fun! And I&rsquo;ve also been to XOXO 2018, which was probably even better than 2016 and Portland already feels like a second home for me.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t plan to travel a lot this year and yet I count 10 (wow) different trips abroad, and most of these were for fun. I&rsquo;ve been to Linz, Berlin, Gothenburg, Vienna, Amsterdam, San Francisco, Portland, Geneva, London.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really know yet what 2019 will bring. If the quote/job I mentioned above works out, I&rsquo;ll be very busy, and that&rsquo;s something I miss. If not&hellip; we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>Hey look, 300 words!</p>

<footer>
    <a title="Permanent link to “A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019”" href="https://blog.ktamas.com/index.php/2018/12/30/a-recap-of-2018-and-what-to-come-in-2019/">A Recap of 2018 and What&#39;s to Come in 2019</a>
    by KTamas for <a href="https://blog.ktamas.com/">KTamas&#39; Blog</a>
    Tagged
        <div class="tags">
            <i class="fas fa-tags"></i>
            <a href='/tags/thoughts/'>thoughts</a>, <a href='/tags/recaps/'>recaps</a>
        </div>
</footer>]]></content>
	</entry>
</feed>
